About 2,000 years ago
Medical Saint zhāng zhòng jǐng (transliteration)
Only look at one point in time
can prescribe medicine
Treat liver disease and ascites
True or false
Can time heal diseases?
Really, I'm telling you.
To treat liver disease,
When to choose
Did you know
Spring morning
At this time
This is when the liver qi is at its peak.
Best for liver treatment
Human physique and time
are closely related
What about today?
I'll tell you
This physical constitution code
How is it calculated?
Hu Naiwen starts his lecture
I'm your old friend, Dr. Hu.
I want to share this episode with you
1.One trick to identify 5 physical constitution. Which one are you?
2.Eat according to the 5 physical constitutions to improve chronic issues.
Grandpa's hilarious answer to his granddaughter's question
One trick to identify your physical constitution. Which one are you?
How to judge
Which physical constitution are you?
From the moment you were born
Hey, you have a set of physical constitution codes
We can use
Researched by the ancients
The so-called Heavenly Stems and Earthly Branches
This time system
Paired with the wǔ xíng (transliteration)
can
Calculate it
Which type of physical constitution are you?
How to take care of your body
to be the healthiest
It sounds complicated.
You can teach us
A simpler one?
no problem
I'll share it now
A simple way for you
You can know your physical constitution
Even your child
What kind of physique
You can all know
This method is
What season were you born in?
Listen carefully now.
There are a total of five physical constitutions
Wood, Fire, Earth, Metal, Water
correspond
Spring, Summer, Autumn and Winter
This method is
What month were you born in?
That month
happened to be
Spring
It's called Wood type person
In summer, people are called Fire type person
In autumn, it is called the Golden type person
In winter, it is called water type person
In the middle there is
Born in the months of Chén xū chǒu wèi (transliteration)
That's called Earth type person
Judging your constitution by your birth season
It is a simple
and practical classification method
If you want more accuracy?
Then we have to
You need to use the bā zì rì zhǔ tiān gān (transliteration)
That's a more advanced version.
Learn this trick first in this episode
It's already very useful.
Metal physical constitution
Eat 1 color food to nourish the lungs and moisten dryness
If you have the Metal physique
What health issues should we pay attention to?
Are you
Coughing when exposed to air conditioning
A change of seasons
Just sneeze
Yes or no
This is the typical metal physical constitution
People with this constitution are prone
to nasal allergies
cough
constipate
Because the lungs and large
are different
from others
What can you eat to replenish your body?
Sydney
Chinese yam
White fungus, etc.
White food nourishes the lungs
the lungs and rùn zào (transliteration)
Please pay attention
In the summer
Don't do it all day
Just blowing air conditioning
Just drinking cold drinks
Too much cold qi on the body
You will cough easily
Really?
My friend is metal physical constitution
Get up in the morning
have a runny nose all the time
sneeze
Then toilet paper
is like making dumplings
A lot of packs
Just like you said
Maybe
This might be
The so-called metal physical constitution
Wood type person
Comb your hair often
Comb your hair regularly and eat these two dishes to soothe liver and relieve depression.
The second physical constitution
called Wood type person
This kind of person
Often
Creative ideas
Is it recently
The mood is also quite depressed.
Dry eyes and poor sleep
People with woodtype personshould pay attention to
It's hisGān huǒ (transliteration)
There will be more
Dry eyes and depressed mood
Still often
A belly full of
anger
Give you a set
Wood type person's Health Preservation Combination
Soothe the liver and relieve depression
Eat more
spinach
celery
These green foods
Comb your hair 30 times
Tap the gān jīng (transliteration) before going to bed
How to pat the gān jīng (transliteration)?
Use hollow palm
From the inner thigh
pat the inner side of the calf
Now pat the gān jīng (transliteration)
Start from the left
How many times did we pat
Three pats, okay.
pat from the top down
Then pat on the right side
The same hands are empty
Exhale while patting
This can soothe the liver and regulate qi
Relieve gān yù qì zhì (transliteration)
Why is it best to pat before going to bed?
The running time of the Gān jīng (transliteration) is
1:00 AM to 3:00 AM
Then you are from 11pm to 1am
This is the Zi hour
That's the dǎn jīng (transliteration)
The liver and gallbladder are the same
This is the time to pat
When the qi flows smoothly
The Huǒ qì (transliteration) subsided
Not only sleep well
The complexion is also good
The whole person won't feel easily suffocated
sulking
water type person's Physique
Back pain when tired
Eat wēn bǔ (transliteration) foods
What about the third water type person's Physique?
You were born in winter
Frozen
TheHán qì (transliteration)is particularly severe
Is it easier?
cold hands and feet
Back pain
feel tired
after doing a little more
Extremely tired
often get up in the middle of the night to pee.
Problems with polyuria and nocturia
Trouble sleeping
Pay attention
Just to keep yourself warm
Drink black bean water
Foot soak
Two-pronged approach
Eat some wēn bǔ (transliteration) foods
black sesame seeds
wolfberry
Walnut
Doing this can strengthen the kidneys and nourish the kidneys
Let me tell you the most important thing.
Just don't stay up late
Many people ask
What to do if you have kidney deficiency
The answer is
Get enough sleep first
Staying up late will weaken your kidneys
Kidney deficiency
The whole person is exhausted
Fire type personsuffer from sore mouth and insomnia
Rely on 3 magic weapons to protect your heart and recover
The fourth Physique
called Fire type person
You who were born in summer
Is it passionate?
Hey, loud voice
Friends often say
The sound arrived before you arrived in person.
What need to pay attention to is
Be careful, the huǒ qì (transliteration) will burn too much.
Do you have this situation?
Mouth sores, dry mouth, and dry tongue
Insomnia
besides
throat always seems to be pinched
Shortness of breath
Heart palpitations
What to do?
Teach you three magic weapons to protect your heart
1. Drink a bowl of lotus seed soup
Reduces huǒ qì (transliteration) and protects the heart
This lotus seed
It would be better if can bring the lotus seed heart
Lotus seeds are meant to remove the heart.
2. Take a deep breath
Calm your mind
3. Meditations
Five to ten minutes
Calm down and you won't be impatient
Earth type person Yam, Job's tears, and millet
Eat well and be full
The fifth Physique Earth type person
You have a natural sense of stability.
Good interpersonal relationships
Is the most popular person
in the workplace and in the circle of friends
Your health problems
Often
Weak spleen and stomach
Easy to bloating
Prone to heavy shī qì (transliteration)
I recommend three good foods to you
Chinese yam
Coix
Millet
Regular consumption
can strengthen the spleen and stomach
Remind you of one thing
Ice cream and cold drinks
Just drink less
In order to improve the spleen and stomach
Keep healthy
The knowledge of the ancients
How can it be so profound?
I'm curious.
They don't have internet.
How do know
so much?
Hey
Do you think ancient people didn't have the Internet?
No AI
Doesn't he understand health preservation?
wrong
They rely on something more powerful
than artificial intelligence
Brain training modules
They observe people's appearance every day
Observing the sky at night
Look up at the stars
Looking down is to see the grass and trees
The whole nature
It's their database
One flower, one world
A leaf, a universe
They figured out a set of time codes
From the changes of temperature
in the four seasons and the changes of plants and animals.
called the Heavenly Stems and Earthly Branches
This is a timemedicine
that combines
astronomical climate and physiology.
There are three major benefits
can check fortune
can judge health by looking at your constitution
Live a good life
In my clinical experience
I also use the Heavenly Stems and Earthly Branches
This set of time medicine
Treat different difficult and complicated diseases
It is a set
A complete domain that has been passed down for thousands of years
What are the Heavenly Stems and Earthly Branches?
How powerful is it
tell you right away
Let me first talk about the Heavenly Stems.
The Heavenly Stems are
Jia, Yi, Bing, Ding, Wu, Ji(transliteration)
Geng, Xin, Ren, and Gui(transliteration), ten
Let’s talk about the Earthly Branches
The Earthly Branches are
Zǐ,chǒu,yín,mǎo,chén,sì (transliteration)
Wǔ,wèi,shēn,yǒu,xūh,ài(transliteration)
These twelve
Each earthly branch
Corresponding to a Chinese zodiac sign.
Zǐ,chǒu,yín,mǎo,chén,sì (transliteration)
Wǔ,wèi,shēn,yǒu,xūh,ài(transliteration)
Corresponding
Rat, ox, tiger, rabbit, dragon, snake
horse, sheep, monkey, chicken, dog, pig
Can you speak Taiwanese?
I really
This test stumped me.
Give it a try
Rat, ox, tiger, rabbit, dragon, snake,horse, sheep, monkey, chicken, dog, pig
Great!
Here comes the point
Your Heavenly Stems correspond to your Five Elements
How to calculate your own Heavenly Stems?
From the year you were born
can see it
Jia and Yi are associated with wood, so you need to take care of your liver
Bing and Ding are associated with fire, so you need to nourish your heart.
Wu and Ji are associated with earth, so you need to nourish your spleen and stomach
Geng and Xin are associated with metal, so you need to protect your lungs
Ren and Gui are associated with water, so you need to nourish your kidneys.
Let me give you an example
Like the editor
He said he was born in 1993
In 1993, his Heavenly Stem was Gui.
So he was said to be a water type person
To nourish the kidneys and take care of the bones
The granddaughter asked
Grandpa's answer to the truth is hilarious
Last time
My granddaughter asked me a question
I almost couldn't answer.
What she said
She said grandma
The cat
Cats are cute
She said it was in the Chinese zodiac
Why didn't it line up?
granddaughter
Grandpa knows
This story
There is a hilarious
and somewhat scheming ending behind it
A long time ago
When humans
didn't know how to count years
Go ask the yù huáng dà dì (transliteration) for help
yù huáng dà dì (transliteration) say's ok
Then I will choose twelve animals
How about being a chinese zodiac sign?
Who ran to me first
can become
the patron saint of the animal world
This chinese zodiac competition
Cat and mouse
They all signed up
But the two of them
None of them can swim
Then an idea struck
Two guys
Jump onto the cow's back
Then hitchhike across the river
It seems that are almost at the end.
The mouse pushed the cat
into the water
He ran away
Ran ashore
Grabbed the first place
As a result, Niu came in second.
So you see us
This chinese zodiac sign
order
Rat, ox, tiger, rabbit, rat comes first
The second genus of cattle
Then other
Poor cat
swam ashore desperately only to find
Wow, the twelve spots are already full.
The cat was so angry that it jumped up and down
Mouse, you scheming ghost
Come to tease me
That's it
Someone said
Some people say revenge on the mouse
Cat sees mouse
It will want to catch it
Yes, that's how it is.
Later, saw a cat chasing a mouse.
It is very likely
The sequel to the century-long grudge
of the twelve chinese zodiac animals
The performance hasn't finished yet.
granddaughter
Did grandpa help you solve the mystery?
Dear fans,
We have opened the membership channel
If you agree with Dr. Hu's promotion of Chinese medicine
The concept of taking care of your own health
Small monthly donations are welcome
Or become a VIP sponsor
With you
We can go further
Thank you so much